<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Weekly Notes on $ls /home/rohit/</title><link>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/</link><description>Recent content in Weekly Notes on $ls /home/rohit/</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Weekly Notes 2023 W30</title><link>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w30/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 17:08:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w30/</guid><description>Last Week(2023W30) This week was low on productivity, but I was able to get good sleep (more than 7 hours). Hopefully, this streak of good sleep continues.
Duration of sleep each day
When I am Going to bed and waking up
I have restarted using ActivityWatch, but I forget to turn it on regularly, and I am still facing issues in getting it to work with systemd (or some other way to launch it on boot).</description></item><item><title>Weekly Notes 2023 W29</title><link>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w29/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 20:42:06 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w29/</guid><description>I missed adding notes for W26, W27, and W28 due to ongoing sleep issues and low productivity, which left me with little energy to gather my thoughts and write. Although I continue to log things in logseq, compiling and fixing the grammar consumes much of the energy I lack.
W26, W27, W28 Weeks W26 to W28 were primarily focused on work with only a few noteworthy events: But here are things I would like to document:</description></item><item><title>Weekly Notes 2023 W25</title><link>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 18:37:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w25/</guid><description>Last Week (2023W25) My sleep continues to improve, but I have failed in my goal of waking up a bit earlier to have a calm day. I&amp;rsquo;m happy and proud that even on days when I worked late, I managed to get home and sleep instead of falling asleep at my desk chair - progress 🎉.
This week was mostly dedicated to work. I had productive days for the most part, successfully completing tasks for both of my projects.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Notes 2023 W24</title><link>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w24/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 04:41:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w24/</guid><description>Last Week (2023W24) I have been sleeping more regularly, and have been sleeping on my bed rather than on a chair, I&amp;rsquo;ll call that progress. I have been going to bed by the early morning hours and waking up by 1500. I&amp;rsquo;m not particularly fond of this schedule because I have to rush through to make it to my calls on time in the evening. However, at least my sleep routine has become somewhat consistent.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Notes 2023 W23</title><link>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 19:50:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w23/</guid><description>It has been approximately 2 months since I last wrote my weekly notes. Forming habits is weird with ADHD. I follow through for some time, and I really like it as well, but then life happens and I slip off. I remember that I am off track, but it gets also lost in the background noise of life.
This also makes it difficult to start new habits because I end up mourning even before things go bad and have a sense of doom that always around the corner.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Notes 2023 W14</title><link>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w14/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 19:22:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w14/</guid><description>Last Week (2023W14) I realized after publishing my last week&amp;rsquo;s note that I have completed one month of weekly notes.
I am writing this on a Tuesday evening because on Sunday, I worked the whole day on a side project.
The first half of last week was mostly productive, but also a bit of a struggle.
I walked every day for the first half of the week for about 20 minutes, but I dropped it during the second half.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Notes 2023 W13</title><link>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 13:55:48 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w13/</guid><description>Last Week (2023W13) April is here.
I got pranked accidentally by this 4-year-old video by EEVblog. In this video, EEVblog claims that because FeCl3 is mixed with water in really minute quantities, it should be possible to etch PCB using it if we can concentrate it, and proceeds to use a magnet to concentrate the said FeCl3 from the running tap water. This did flare up my BS detector, but given it was an old video and it was EEVBlog, I thought it was legit.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Notes 2023 W12</title><link>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 11:51:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w12/</guid><description>Last week (2023W12) I am writing this on a Monday morning, instead of Saturday or Sunday night.
Last week I had some good progress in my work. I am working with my therapist to fix my sleep cycle and irregular food habits.
Monday was very productive. I made good progress on the work front.
Tuesday I spent a few hours reading through a lot of blogs. I added a lot of them into my feed reader.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Notes 2023 W11</title><link>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w11/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 23:46:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w11/</guid><description>This week Nibling++: My cousin, with whom I spent countless summer vacations growing up, is now a proud parent. It&amp;rsquo;s crazy how fast time flies and how life changes.
Update on Tempus: Starting of this week, I spent some time working on Tempus. I changed the orientation to landscape and added code to display the keypad and identify key presses. However, I noticed that there were some issues with a single key press being interpreted as a series of key presses, so I plan to add some debouncing or filtering features to fix this problem.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Notes 2023-W10</title><link>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 01:40:57 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-2023-w10/</guid><description>This week Last Sunday Night, I had my Dinner at Salt Mango Tree with a friend. I Loved their Kreme Kerala and Malabar Biryani. It just soothes the soul. Kreme Kerala
As someone with ADHD, I&amp;rsquo;ve always struggled with Time Agnosia, making it difficult to balance my work and personal life while maintaining good habits. To help combat this, I started working on a side project called Tempus this week.</description></item><item><title>Weekly Notes 2023-W09</title><link>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-week-09-2023/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 18:25:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/weekly-notes/weekly-notes-week-09-2023/</guid><description>I follow Thej&amp;rsquo;s weekly notes and wanted to write my own. I am not sure what would go here - but here is the first edition.
Last year Last year I got diagnosed with ADHD. I had a hunch for sometime, but getting it officially diagnosed was helpful. Knowing about ADHD has helped me in understanding myself, mainly the fact that my behaviour and patterns are not a moral failure.</description></item></channel></rss>