<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on $ls /home/rohit/</title><link>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on $ls /home/rohit/</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 14:42:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Confession of a New Atheist</title><link>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/post/confessions-of-a-new-atheist/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 14:42:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/post/confessions-of-a-new-atheist/</guid><description>Confession of a New Atheist This morning, I am in urgent need of a God. It would be nice if I could order faith (that I have lost) over at https://amazon.in - same-day delivery guaranteed.
I&amp;rsquo;m feeling helpless and hopeless. I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to tame myself or my flaws. I yearn to kneel before someone greater than myself and submit, hoping they will fix everything.
I see and understand why the notion of God exists, and why even intellectuals like Dr.</description></item><item><title>Periodic reminders for Interstitial journaling</title><link>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/post/interstitial-automate-logseq/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 08:01:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/post/interstitial-automate-logseq/</guid><description>I first came across Interstitial Journaling from this post by Nesslabs a long time back. I used it for some time (few hours at most!).
My ADHD makes it difficult for me to be aware of the passage of time when I am either in hyperfocus or procrastination mode. Additionally, not having a solid system to log it was bothering me. Where should I store this file? What would be the easiest way to give it a timestamped name?</description></item><item><title>This Morning Jan 11 2022</title><link>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/post/this-morning-jan-11-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 14:48:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/post/this-morning-jan-11-2022/</guid><description>It was very early in the morning when I went to bed yesterday. I decided to stay back in the office yesterday night. Waking up by noon, I went through some emails and then decided to make myself a cup of coffee before jumping into the day.
Shashank has been bringing Bruce to the office regularly in the mornings, so Bruce gets familiarized with the office environment.
I spent some time with Shashank and Bruce in our office garden, grinding my coffee beans.</description></item><item><title>Team Outing, Ramnagara, Jan 2022</title><link>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/post/team-outing-ramnagara-jan-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:56:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/post/team-outing-ramnagara-jan-2022/</guid><description>2021 has been a difficult time for the whole world, and it was not different for us @Beneathatree. We had teammates who braved through COVID, who met with an accident and recovered. We grieved the loss of dear ones, and we were also in an absolute panic because we were about to lose someone very near to all of us.
2021 had something good too. Our clients reached a lot of their milestones in their journey.</description></item><item><title>Em and the Big Hoom</title><link>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/post/em-and-the-big-hoom/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 20:36:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/post/em-and-the-big-hoom/</guid><description>Disclaimer
This is NOT a book review.
I do not feel comfortable judging something of which I do not have a complete understanding. I am a very naive reader and, this is just a documentation of things that the book made me feel through the process of reading it.
Living with Em, having survived her into adolescence, we’d earned the right to be her equals.
‘Will it comfort you?</description></item><item><title>Hello World!</title><link>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/post/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 22:47:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kernelanxiety.dev/post/hello-world/</guid><description>Hello world!
I love coming across blogs from the 2000s that document an era in tech and society that I lived through but know nothing about. I love blogs that are more of a diary, a running commentary of a thought process of the project than a straightforward tutorial.
I do not plan to do any of those. But I wanted to keep a log of things I dabble in, read, and other random things that I do, outside of my day-to-day work.</description></item></channel></rss>